Okay.
How about you, Eric? What are you gonna name yourself, my dear?
Just Big Kahuna.
What?
>> Big Kahuna.
It's gotta be something about ice sailing, my dear.
What's what's the who's the best ice sailor?
What do you what is what's the name for that?
Kahuna
Surfer.
>> That would be the world champion, which I definitely am not. Okay.
>> So we're going to give Curtis a couple more minutes or plow on ahead without him? Oh, I can text him.
>> Hey, Eric. Can I ask you a question while we're waiting for Kurt? Absolutely.
Ask away.
>> I do well, first of all, what do I look like? Is do I have a just like a blank gray icon from on your screens? What do I have a screen? No.
It's just a picture of a telephone.
>> Yeah. Okay. That's me. Alright. Well, this is a big step for me. So next time I'll get the visual going too.
Last time was on my wife's computer. She's working from home. So I was able to use that, but not tonight. I'm trying the iPhone. But anyway no. Quick question. The the chip seal is looking good.
There's there's just some concerns I had. I wish we had the time
and the manpower to fix certain big depressions in the road before we chip seal them. They're overall,
a lot of you know, 90% of the roads are in good shape, needed just the chip seal, but some
spots were depressed. I measured, like, a dip of at least four inches. So what we're see this winter
is we're gonna see that pocket still holding water even better because it's the cracks aren't letting the water through now. So
I wish we had the time to do some
re
or releveling
with some hot mix in certain
specific locations before we chip sealed?
>> Yep. That would have been nice.
But I mean,
you know, I got by my estimation right now,
I've got about a half million dollars in shimming I need to do, and I got about $75,000
to do it. So I'm not going to do most of what I wanted to do for shimming.
Yeah. Obviously, we passed on a lot of roads because they required too much shimming
before we could
chip seal.
You know, we chip seal basically everything we could get away without doing and you're right, there are some depressions.
It's far from perfect.
>> You know, we could always, we could, we could always come back and do it in a future year if that can these areas, little areas continue to be problems when and they will. But it would have been just nice to do to spend a week going around with this with us with a box
a drag box and
filling in the
severe
depressions in spots that have now been chip sealed, but we could always fix it in years come future, I guess. Yeah, I mean, the reality is our costs,
>> our day rate costs,
you know, are somewhere around $5,000
plus trucking,
plus asphalt at around $70
a ton.
I mean,
you know, like I said, I think I've got more than a half $1,000,000
of shimming I'd like to be able to do in town,
I don't even have a fifth of that, you know, in actual money.
Do
>> we we do we even still have a drag box to put in the back of a dump truck? No, we do not.
>> Oh, well that there you go. We can't we can't do it anyways then. Oh, we're not doing it. No, we can't. We don't have the drag box number one. We don't have a roller that works number two.
Right. Right. Okay. Alright. You know, okay.
Yeah, we're pretty limited in what we can do in that. We're
Unfortunately,
we're stuck with subbing all of that out What we are gonna try this fall for potholes
is something called the dura patcher
Yeah, I'm gonna try to rent one for a month
So basically you just buy the liquid asphalt emulsion
and you fill the back of the the dump truck up with stone
and The stone pours out on little conveyor belt it gets mixed right on the spot with the emulsion
You know and stuffed into the into the potholes.
So it seems a good way to make a pretty permanent pothole repair
equivalent to doing it with hot mix.
You end up with a little more asphalt
than it and a little less aggregate,
but you can do it fast. So you have the ability to do a lot in a short time.
>> Yeah. Most of them develop in February and March,
as you probably know.
>> Yeah. But you know what? We've got so many potholes to fill now. I'm not even worried about new potholes.
I'm worried about potholes that already exist.
>> Right. Okay. Oh, you're talking about real small patching. Okay. Yeah. I gotcha.
Yeah. Okay. Alright.
Kurt
here yet. Kurt
>> didn't respond to my text, so I think we need to get going. Let's call to order without Curtis.
That's at 07:11.
711.
And that's where Kurt is.
>> And so
Eric.
Ed. So, Louise, why are hiding from us?
Why? You wanna see me?
It's
nice.
Alright.
Hi.
Hey. We we harassed Ed so Outside.
Oh. That's great.
What?
>> We called to order at 07:11.
I've got the roll
and
public comment.
Additions or changes to the agenda?
That
>> bird was perfect.
This is good. Without Adrienne, we'll move right along here.
Approval
of minutes for the prior meeting. Shannon.
>> I move to approve the minutes.
I second. Forward by you of the prior meeting.
Shannon I seconded.
I'll second it.
Do we have any discussion?
This is going well. Okay.
All in favor?
Aye.
All right.
I love those birds.
Okay project
>> update discussion
this was from Curtis
so
I don't know who's going be Kurt's proxy but I
guess this is you Eric what's what's been going on? Okay, so from the fire department front,
>> the fire department
sometime in July
will receive their new fire truck. They have apparently done a virtual walk through
tour of the truck before it left the factory. It's going to some place in New Haven
for,
I don't know, like a few weeks of additional work and stuff being installed
and then they're supposed to have that sometime in July,
and I'm gonna sign a big fat check for I think around $412,000
and we're gonna have a shiny new fire truck. This is So
>> I'm sorry go ahead. No that's it. Completes questions. We had on our minutes before that this was supposed to come in June 1. Did I get that date wrong?
>> I think it came into New Haven on June 1. Oh, okay. We're not gonna have it for
we'll have it fairly soon though. Okay.
And we'll make Kurt buy us all, you know, invite us all to a to a party where we're gonna celebrate the new truck,
and there'll be fireworks,
you know, maybe a band that's
probably not, but you never know.
>> We approved $4.20 for it if you're only spending $4.12 that's
>> That's true. That's true. We could have a hell of a party for $8.
Yeah, so
that is on its way. We also as CIP had approved
the purchase of the UTV
for the fire department.
I signed a purchase order for that yesterday or the day before. So that is,
it will be delivered hopefully in a couple weeks.
They got to put the MEDI insert in the back
and but it looks like that should be delivered in roughly,
you know the same time frame within the next month.
The fire department is going to end up working for a while to install because they still got to install radios
and they got to do a bunch of the work. They've opted to do a lot of the work themselves as opposed to
farming it out.
So that's it for the
fire department.
There's
a couple other things. We just got in the blower for the roadside mower that has arrived
and we got a CIP approved the purchase of the material hoist
for the loader. So we've got that and that's been put to work pretty extensively in rebuilding
the transfer station walls.
Those
are it for what's come in for public works.
Their the work on the transfer station
is ongoing,
it's coming reasonably well,
we
you know,
most of the electrical conduit is in
a lot of the electrical work.
Basically, one of the things we realized, we realized a couple things when we started that project.
The first is the CIP approved money for a shed and some electrical work and then they separately approved money to do the walls.
So we didn't approve enough money to do all concrete walls.
We did one side with a conventional block
and we did the others we're going to do the other we're doing the other side now with more of a retaining wall style block.
Advantages and disadvantages to both,
we had some real problems with the first side that we did that the blocks were poured pretty unevenly
even though we paid a fair amount of money for them and we specified new pour air and train you know, high strength concrete
and we got that, but we didn't get, you know, square and level blocks.
So we're redoing it with a slightly different type of block for the other side.
That part of it's going well.
Where we are, we're way over budget on a couple things.
The first is that we are slightly changing the configuration,
the layout of that side.
And we're basically,
what we're doing is we're setting the facility up so at some point in the future we can add a fourth compactor if we need to and there are some definite advantages to that. Oh,
like we lost somebody.
Oh well.
Louis dropped out.
So, but that's requiring us to pour,
extend one of the pads,
concrete pads that the compactors
are on.
So we're going to run some expenses for that.
The other big expense
is
we made a decision
to abandon
what we were using.
We had been using static phase converters to produce the three phase electricity
and we've been struggling with that for a long time.
Basically what happened is we used to have a rotary phase converter in there and it broke and instead of just replacing it,
Bob took the cheapest solution that was possible,
which was put in these little static phase converters one for each machine.
The problem being they only produce
essentially two thirds of the rated power when they're running
and they've caused us a bunch of failures with the compactors.
So we're basically
redoing the electrical system and that's fairly expensive,
But we have enough money in the contingency budget to do it,
so we're just kind of rolling with it.
Eric, are you going to be putting replacing
>> them with rotaries so that you get Yeah, so what we're doing is we're putting in one large enough rotary phase converter
that is capable of running two compactors at a time.
So
it's a fairly large unit
and what we did is we're basically
essentially what we're doing is we're starting from the service drop
and we're replacing everything from the service drop.
New meter,
new main service panel,
rotary phase, three phase converter,
three phase panel right next to it, poured on a concrete pad and then underground trenching. We got rid of the overhead wire. We're going all underground
and part of the reason we swapped out the overhead wire
or we got rid of that is we had so many trees we had to take down that have overgrown the wires
that we were looking at like a $6,000
bill for tree trimming,
you know, because we had to cut around the wires and we had to bring somebody in with a bucket to do it. So in the end, we saved ourselves some money on that part by just eliminating everything overhead
and we're putting everything in conduit which will be a lot safer
and it will be all run back to the transfer station attendance
booth.
There will be low voltage wiring to that so all the controls for the three phase converter
will be in the attendance booth so he can turn it on and turn it off in the in the evening right from the booth.
Know and then we got rid of the old building,
the old little
crappy building and we've got a new prefab one that will be arriving as soon as the pad's ready for it.
So I would say that project is coming along very well.
I was unhappy that we had as much mission creep
as we did, and there could have even been a lot more mission creep. I mean, there's still plenty of other stuff to replace too.
But
at the end of the day, what we need to do is have functional compactors that work every time you hit the little button.
And we've
really been struggling with that for the past year.
>> Agreed, Eric. Eric, quick question on that. Has
Jerry Hardesty helped you with any of the engineering on that? Sounds with the commission creep, there's a lot of important documentation.
For instance, the location
of the underground power feed. Has a site plan been made? When I worked there, there was there wasn't even a site plan at all. Is any any drawings been made of this?
We have schematic
drawings from electrician.
>> Hold on one sec, Eric, before you continue. Louise is saying she can't get back in. Are you as the administrator, can you see if she's trying to trying to get back in and she can't? She just texted me.
>> I'm certainly not blocking her from getting in.
There's nothing on my end that prevents her from getting in. Okay. Sorry to interrupt.
Yep. No worries. Alright.
>> So my my only advice is to try to get, you know, as much of this documented so in the future, you know, ten, twenty years from now, we know where everything is and what it's been built with.
>> Right.
Right. So
so we have fairly careful documentation
on like, we're basically where we're running the conduits,
you know, and all the wiring schematics for it.
So we have that,
you know, we have the block documentation
for what we're using for blocks.
You
>> know, we could do better, no question. It would have been nice to
start with, you know, a fully surveyed piece,
you know, but we did not. There were a couple of really interesting things we discovered when we started digging.
The first is they never we always wondered why
the moisture
never really drained
from under the moisture that went through the road didn't drain
and that was when
they had the original when it was still just the
Just the actual dump
that was a paved road underneath
and They never took out the road They just piled more gravel on top to create the grade
and paved another road So you dig down and you hit a second road underneath the first road, which is kind of unfortunate because that, you know, by putting gravel over it, you do a great job of preserving it because it doesn't get sunlight.
So now you put like a waterproof barrier right in the middle of this thing. So it's Yeah. Yeah. The impervious later so the water can't the water can't percolate down into the groundwater it belongs. Yeah. Right. Okay.
You know, but I mean, what are you gonna do? You know, there's no there's no possible way we can dig the whole thing out.
There's some pretty serious constraints with it.
>> I had made some sketches for Joe
a couple of years ago. He needed to know what was there. I just
me and Dave pulled dimensions on the existing walls. And we made a schematic drawing of to to be able to we're studying whether to use larger dumpsters or not. We're pretty much confined to the dumpsters we're using because of the wall configuration.
And if we're just replacing in kind, that's fine too. We're just gonna keep the same size dumpsters. I mean, there's a lot to consider.
Also, I had told Joe about a seminar I went to the DEEP
where someday they may require us to put a roof over those dumpsters. So,
you know, we could just do a full structure if we have to in the future, which means we might have to drill
some telephone poles into the ground. But,
again, documentation, we need to know where that those cables where that electrical cables are so we're not drilling into cables in the future.
>> So, Eric, you said we're over budget on that. So you said money came from?
>> Yeah. So so we're gonna take the excess money out of contingency.
So to put in perspective, the electrical work alone was about $35,000
and that's what accounts for the difference.
The rotary phase converter itself
was quite a bit. That was over that was around 5,000 just for that.
New main service panel, new meter socket,
the original service drop was really
in rough shape.
So we've kind of just elected to
practically
start over from the pole on.
It sucks that we have to do it but there wasn't enough there
to really
everything we looked at the main service panel had some pretty serious rust issues so you were going to replace that.
The meter socket had some problems so we're going to replace that.
The service drop they never put in conduit it was just bare cable,
when the cable was all cracked and checked. So it's like every time you go back one step, you're like, oh, I guess that's got to come out too.
So hopefully
we end up with a lasting solution
and we're not screwing around with this thing,
you know,
>> but Yeah, it's good. It's good we went out underground.
There's nothing else for power for storms,
for ice storms and things.
>> And so is that why the compactors
would go out every once in a while? Just the motors weren't getting enough electricity?
>> That was a big part of it, yeah. And then we'd blow the
breaker on the static phase converter,
And after it cooled down, sometimes it would start again,
sometimes
it wouldn't.
Yeah,
but
the thing is that if you're running a three phase system,
the static converters really only drive the third phase
the instant of the starting current and the rest of the time they're basically they're driving off two
legs not three.
And that's
a third of your power that's
missing. So you're running a 10 horse compact or at six and a half
horse.
So
it doesn't take much of a
jam or much in
the way before that thing just locks up and won't go anywhere.
>> Okay.
Well, I'm glad we're getting it done right after all these years.
>> Yeah, sounds like you're doing it right. You're doing it right, I'm trying. I'm trying.
>> We are looking at,
you know, that's pretty much it for there.
I still want to consider at some point figuring out how we can do a ductless
split system for the town hall.
The window air conditioners we have are really marginal for this space,
and they're really inefficient.
So given what we're spending on
electricity,
I think long term we need to come up with some kind of reasonable solution for this building.
You know, but I don't know that I'm going to get to that this year.
If I do, I would probably plan on tapping LOSIP money to do it,
because
one of the things I did was I looked back through all the the town's previous LOSIP projects.
>> Hold on. Ed just dropped off and he'll probably wanna hear this and Louise can't get in.
So she's dropped out of the meeting. I don't know what her issue, she said she's having buffering issues.
Every time she tries to get in it buffers.
>> Yeah, I saw she, it looked like she was on a pretty low bandwidth
connection. She could probably just call in on her phone,
you know, and do audio only.
>> Yeah, it's probably better for her to do audio only if she's running low, whether on computer or phone.
>> I could tell you at my house if I'm you know I can't do video
I can call in but you know it kicks me out all the time because I don't have enough bandwidth to to really do it.
We'll wait a couple minutes and see whether Ed can get back on.
>> Well I'm glad you're getting the, the transfer station done right. It'd be nice to have that
to have that up and running the way it should. I wondered why those things seem to break down all the time
paying the price of Bob's cheapness, the high cost to low prices.
>> You got it.
Doesn't matter what you can do, you can always half ass it, Fred. Yeah.
>> Why pay a little now when you can pay a lot later?
>> You know, some things just make me crazy like if you ever drove out to Cone Road,
most of Cone Road was paved like eight,
you know,
eight years ago, seven years ago.
That road needs to be ground up and done over. I mean, it I hate to say it, but it really needs kind of a complete
do over,
which is crazy for an eight year old road,
you know, but they boarded on top of a gravel road,
they never got the sub base right, they never got the drainage right,
Bob wanted to pave it and they paved it, you know and
>> Yep,
wow
Well the bitterness of low quality lingers long after the
the sweet taste of low prices recede
>> Eric, were you going give us an update, my dear, on what's going on with
the new website?
Yep.
>> Okay. Nope, you can wait on that.
I don't wanna yep. Wait. I asked Louise to try audio only so we have a quorum.
I don't I know if I have Ed's.
What is quorum for us?
Four, I think.
>> So now we're at two because Eric's not on our
Right.
Part of us.
>> Is it I
don't know. I never heard back from Kurt.
>> One, two, three, four, five, six.
Yeah, it's supposed to be a seven member board,
but if only three or only
six are appointed, yeah I guess quorum would still be four.
It can't be half.
I'm all ready.
>> Well I could go downstairs and Fred and I could talk to you Eric.
The only thing I have for Ed Zorisley is a phone number an email. Do you have a phone number for him, Eric?
>> Let me check actually. I might have.
Yep.
I'll call him.
Yeah. Can you give it to us?
>> Oh. Sure. As soon as I I'm done calling him, I'll give I
have a number for Ed. What's his number, honey?
>> Is it a home or work number or cell number? I think it's a cell. 498-1084.
Hold on.
498-1084.
>> Hey Ed, it's Eric. Just poking
you and seeing whether
you kind of dropped off real quick. Thought you probably dropped the call. I'm wondering if you're trying to get back on
only
via
phone.
Give me a callback or
or not. Thanks. Bye.
Hey! Oh got
Oh
okay
cool. You might be able to get on audio only and that might help.
Okay. Yep. Cheers.
He's trying to get back on even as we speak.
>> Well, we still need Louise. We need four.
We need four board members. So without without Louise, we can't. This is not official.
Well, it was official when we started.
>> Is that you Louise or is that Ed? That's me. Alright.
Okay. So
>> we dropped Ed too. We're trying to get Ed back so we have Quorum and we can,
have an official meeting.
Yeah there's network issues going on I think there's
>> CD's
all
right well now we're official at least surprise surprise
hey Curtis good to see you
you're muted Kurt
>> Sorry. I'm late. Had to take the grandson home and, got tied up.
Understood.
It was a it was a trying day. Trust me. And
all I'll say is he got into a black permanent magic marker.
Nice.
>> And decided to, you know, to join the crew of, Black Lives Matter. So
Excellent.
That's all I can say.
So if you save pictures, could blackmail them later on in life. I have pictures. Trust me. I had send them to his mother.
>> Yeah. So when he runs for public office later, this blackface is gonna come back to haunt him. He had black face, he had black legs, he had black hands, arms. He's done for. Oh my lord. Anyways,
that's all I got. All right, Kurt. Well, thank you for joining us. We were doing an update, Eric, at your
request.
Yeah. Doing a project update.
Good. I
guess you'll get the minutes when I do that. I don't want to ask Eric to go through all that stuff. Right.
>> Know exactly what Eric's
doing and it
looks like it's coming out pretty good. So far so good. Yeah. Okay. Yeah. So please carry on, Mr. Anderson.
>> So Shannon asked a question about what was happening with the
website.
So the town's website new website is about
probably 80%,
85%
finished.
We're not ready to share links with you yet for the
updated site, but that should be within
a couple of weeks.
We're originally looking at July 8 to go live
with the cut over to the new site.
I suspect we're not gonna make that.
We had about a month, month and a half delay from Civic.
I'm not sure exactly why, you know, our program
manager
there was,
you know, I think stringing us along
and we finally got fed up with it and, you know, bitched enough and they gave us a new project lead
and now things are
banging right along. So we're doing a lot better with that.
I think we,
at some point in July, we will have the new website up and running and fully functional,
which would be really good.
We also
are
a long way through our IT upgrade.
We've suffered some pretty serious delays with that
because South Windsor has,
you know, we had expected to get support from a whole series of South Windsor staff
for that from their IT department
and South Windsor has said all their IT people that work on-site in South Windsor can only work on-site
in South Windsor
and the one or two people they have that were servicing other towns,
they're basically kept away from South Windsor.
So we really we have a lot less support
right now for the upgrades than we had, but we're moving along.
We got the new server in, it's functional. We got rid of our oldest server.
The intermediately aged server is now just
gonna be relegated to backup duties.
You know, we're finally for the first time ever doing a legitimate daily backups of all our critical data, all our data period.
Know, and it's a raid.
I'm not an IT guy. It's a raid something something.
So it's the primary data,
a complete backup,
a complete isolated backup of the backup
is how I would describe it.
That's not accessible other than through a password. So it's not at all accessible to the outside.
The next two things we have to do is transition the town to Office 365
for
our email server because as most of you know who've tried to get in touch with us,
our email has been just absurdly bad
the last couple months.
We're also really struggling with keeping our existing website functional.
Site five, our website host,
is just
we've been paying a lot of money
to an outside
web
development
company
to just patch our site together every time it breaks. So we're really looking forward to having the new site up and fully functioning
and getting rid of site five
completely.
And then the last part of that project
is going slower and that is the transition
to fiber.
So we had a meeting with the big shots at CEN,
which is the Connecticut Education Network,
and they own all the fiber infrastructure
that goes by here.
They, so there's basically a hub
in the school. And what we need to do is we need to get and we have a fiber connection
that goes from the town hall
to somewhere in the school. It sounds like the library, at least that's what's written on ours.
And somehow we need to get that fiber connection complete through
to CEN's hub
that's in the school because that hub has plenty of capacity.
And so essentially what we're looking at is running
fiber through the school,
but we won't interface
directly with the school's
system.
So it will just go through the school and try to figure out how to do that.
I'm kind of Question, hoping
>> Eric. When and where did we run the fiber optic underground from town hall to the school?
The answer is I have no idea.
It
>> definitely
exists.
It comes into the building
and we use it, the connection between the town hall
and the school for the financial software
is run through that fiber. The only thing currently run through the fiber
is the financial software because the Phoenix
system is installed on a server in the school
but what's unknown is
so where the fiber comes into the building it says clearly that it's connected
to
the school library
>> But we don't know where in the school library and we're gonna have to do Well, some there's there's a there are two things Eric,
there's the library. It's probably not in the library, but they're the office of the librarian
and right next to the library in that office
is the whole computer lab.
So I would imagine that the server is right there.
It may look like it's library, but it's really the computer lab or the librarian's actual office.
>> Right and if we are lucky
and but we as in the town is lucky
and because
if you look at where the CEN comes into the building it's at the complete upper level opposite end
and it's too long a run for you to have run CAT five. So,
there's a good chance that the school is already running fiber
from CEN
down to that location.
And if they are and you have a spare pair,
then it's
essentially free
and then
CEN just makes the
assigns
that to a router,
you know, so we're not,
you know, we're not scamming off the school system. We're going to pay for the CEN directly.
We'll pay them directly. We're just transmitting
through
the
fiber through the school to get there. That's the plan anyway. I know at one point the town was trying to say, well, we don't need our own connection.
We'll just tie into the school and use theirs. And
that was never going to fly. CEN was never going to approve that.
But the good news from our perspective is the cost for CEN
is the same monthly cost basically as our cost for
that we're paying right now for cable,
and it's somewhere around 50 times greater bandwidth
and much greater in the afternoons when the load is heavy
because especially right now during COVID,
I mean the bandwidth
first thing in the morning,
you know, is pretty good here but by late afternoon it's, you know, it's wicked slow.
So that project I think will go, we just have to coordinate
with
the
IT people and we've started the conversation with you know the the school's IT people,
you know and kept kind of Laura in the loop on that
>> about what's going on. Charles to Christina Fraser is that who you're speaking with? No we're talking to Tom Fleck,
the consultant,
the guys you use for
He's
>> He's
So
it's either going to be really simple and really cheap or we're going to end up running somehow
bringing contractor
in to run fiber the full length of the building to do a direct connection and I'm hoping it's not the latter
because that's a pain in the butt but you know if we have to we have to.
We, you know, we looked at both options either going through the fire department,
you know, or trying to go directly
outside,
but those are both, you know, 16 to $20,000
propositions
going through the school is, you know should be
you know should be pretty low cost.
But you know obviously we got to get the school to agree to it and we got to make sure you know your IT people understand
you know where it has to go and what has to happen. So it's either going to be really inexpensive
because you already had the building rewired
and there's
a spare
pair that we can tap or there isn't in which case we're running wire. So the answer is I don't know working on it.
Anything
else?
>> No there's
we got the sprinkler system fixed finally
for the field. So
the field is up and running finally
that was harder than it's had to be we're having a we had a huge problem with getting sand into the the filtration system
to the point where the way it was rigged up to this point,
somebody had to go up there every single day, remove the filter, clean the filter, reinstall it.
So that that was kind of a problem. We put in a specific sand trap slash sand filtration
system
and a solenoid so that it cleans itself,
you know, a couple times a day. So so far that seems to be working flawlessly.
Seems like we finally may have fixed that.
We've gone after a couple other small electrical problems.
We had some issues at the
museum which we corrected and we're putting in a couple exterior
motion sensor floods for the parking area just for a little security
and so when people are coming back from the rail trail late there's some illumination there.
Know we're still having some other little mechanical problems but nothing's big enough to really trip into CIP
territory
and
you know I don't we don't
really have enough
information to say too much about other things. I should have back
in within the next ten days kind of a comprehensive report on all the culverts in town
and we can start making
you know
educated guests or educated decisions about what ones
you know what the priority
for culvert replacement has to be and you know how many of them are really critical and how many we can put off.
The only other thing is we're moving along with the Bunker Hill Bridge project.
I spoke to the engineer
that's
assigned to us,
the consulting engineer. So far that's going pretty well. They're just waiting on final
federal
approval.
So basically once we get the eight project number
right now we're like over one TBD
and when it goes from you know to be determined to an actual project number that means it's fully funded at the federal level.
They started the environmental surveys,
the wetlands flagging,
the next big thing up will be to do core samples,
you know, and basically we'll have to close one lane at a time while they do core samples,
know, but that project's proceeding.
So it looks like we're far enough into the process
and I believe that bridge we saw them
doing bridge inspections,
you know fairly recently and we haven't gotten any bad news.
So it doesn't seem like this year they're going to close that bridge.
So it seems like we'll get to
the construction phase.
And so the only bridge closure will be during actual construction and we won't be stuck with an initial bridge closure
before that happens.
>> That's all I know about bridges at this point. Okay, so Eric by bridge closure you mean involuntary
bridge closure
because they
would say it's unsafe and you have to close it now.
>> Yeah, the
inspector last year hinted that that was a legitimate possibility
because the bridge rating went down to three out of 10.
And to put it in perspective,
they're eligible for funding when they get to be a six.
I mean, if it was a span bridge and it was ahead of structural rating of three, it would have already been closed.
But because culvert type bridges have more redundancy
and the failures tend to be less catastrophic,
they're allowed to be pushed down farther
down the spectrum
before they start putting weight limits.
And even they actually wouldn't close it, but they would put a low enough weight limit on it that we wouldn't drive buses and we wouldn't drive fire trucks over it. So we really want to get it done before we get to that
point.
And one year old students Ed
is the guy running the Chris the video. Yeah Chris the video is running the project.
Yep, it's good.
All right, that's
>> all for our updates.
Our next
next agenda item is public discussion.
>> I have an update, Fred. Oh, well, please.
Coming on late.
The
fire tanker will be leaving South Dakota tomorrow
en route to Connecticut. Should arrive at the dealership
early next week, and we're hoping to have it in town here on or before next Wednesday.
We're scheduled to have the new radios installed and things like that here at the fire station in town.
I thought it was going to New Haven first. It's going to North Haven. North Haven. Yep. Okay. Yep. They they're they're talking to to get it here from South Dakota, like, two and a half to three days max.
So at least tomorrow, it should be in here by Monday. So
Can they just turn the lights on and drive really fast? Things govern for 50 miles an hour, so you don't really want to be the driver pounding that thing for from South Dakota to Connecticut. I'm sorry. I wouldn't want to. Yeah. I'll do they trailer it in?
No. They drive it. Oh, okay. It's good break in period for it anyways. Most
fire apparatuses,
unless you specifically want it,
trailered in, they're all delivered,
you know,
on their own. So
it's it's good break in for the, for the unit.
Chief Mike is in negotiations
with,
it DH Marvin and Sons in Colchester for a
John Deere,
UTV?
Seems to be he says it's gonna be well well within the budget,
and he's also talking to, Connecticut Trailer in Bolton for the, the trailer at the trailer.
They've had some they got some pretty good sales going on right now for the size trailer that that's needed.
So once he once he confirms that,
you know, we'll be we'll be talking to town hall.
>> Yeah. Kurt, I've already signed the purchase order
to D. H. Marvin for the Four digits.
For the UTV and for the insert.
So that's already in the in the pipes they have. Why why didn't the fire chief tell me that?
>> I don't know. I will take it up with him when I see him. And Wally signed the purchase order.
There's another one. Why didn't Wally tell me that? I don't know why they gave you the mushroom free time. Oh my lord. Okay. That's That's the thing you know, Kurt, your key's not gonna work in the door anymore.
>> Yeah.
When that happens, then I guess I may really retire.
That's really all I had to report as far as the
items that
the capital items that we're working on.
We're happy it's been close to a year to get this truck finally.
And we're all set to go once it does arrive here for
training and outfitting and so on and so forth.
Getting service as soon as possible, hopefully on or before July 1, if everything goes right.
>> Excellent. And we said you were going to throw a big party, a big new truck party.
You were going to fight all of CIP.
>> Not with COVID nineteen.
Sorry.
That's up to that's up to chief Mike anyways and the president, mister Gustanian. They do they handle all of the
all of the good welfare for the department.
>> I say we light a huge bonfire on the beach and have the tanker pump the water up and put it put the bonfire out. We can do that. We can do that. No problem. No
>> problem, Eddie. You know that.
Alright.
So that's that's basically all I had Fred on that. Okay.
>> Thank you, Kurt. Any
other project update?
So that moves us to public comment.
Adjournment.
I move to adjourn.
Shannon moves to adjourn.
Second. Seven fifty five.
This might be a record for us.
>> Kirk, just so you know, I announced at the beginning of the meeting, Adrian's father-in-law has pneumonia.
He had a stroke last week and they were to bring him to a rehab facility today,
but he developed pneumonia last night. So that's why Adrian's not with us and Understand. Keep him in your thoughts. Will do. Thank you. Now his father or father-in-law?
Father-in-law.
Okay. All right. Thanks, Shannon. Thank you.
>> Okay. Well, thank you, everybody, for coming out.
I'll be in touch before the next meeting.
Any expectations for next time around? So Eric you might have some stuff for us for the BRID culverts.
>> I'll probably have a reasonable report for you for the culverts and we can talk about you know what's possible to fund and what's not possible to fund. Right.
You know, all that's going to be money dependent.
Yeah, that that'll be the big things I I come back to you with.
You know, roadwork is proceeding,
And,
>> we'll go from there. Okay. Anything new in the pipeline from the firehouse, Kurt?
>> Not really.
We're
very happy, you know, with the town of street as well in the last few years. So, Yeah, you're doing well. We have nothing, really, really,
pending.
That's good. Not for quite some time so we can build that, fund up and stuff. Yeah. It's Christmas in July, Kurt. Christmas in Yeah.
Is. It is. Anything from the school, Shannon?
No?
>> We're just dealing with, as as everybody knows,
the financial software
between the town and the school and divide deciding on what we're gonna do for financial software. So that needs to be determined.
>> Okay. Yeah. And I I apologize.
I didn't get any meeting notice for that. Adrian asked me afterward why I wasn't on the meeting and I'm like, I really have You weren't no
>> supposed to be on the meeting. It was supposed to be a meeting between
Jeff, Adrian, Chris Bernard, and my
to talk about the to talk about the creation of a financial department.
And I had asked Jeff to set up a Zoom meeting with Amanda
for the four of us.
And Okay.
>> Yeah. You weren't you weren't supposed to be involved in that, my dear. That was the committee that we created after the joint board of selection and board of education meeting. Okay and that's fine Adrian just asked me why it wasn't at the meeting and I'm like I have no idea what you're talking about. You weren't supposed to be.
>> That's great. That's
good then I don't feel bad for blowing you off. Nope.
Okay
okay well thanks everybody.
Alright. Thanks
Yep.